# Karan Samel

# ksamel@gatech.edu (925) 400-3027 https://karans.github.io/

My current research revolves around joining deep learning with symbolic reasoning to reduce the number of labels required. I have also worked on human in the loop learning, and knowledge graph incorporation into deep learning methods, and medical applications.

**EDUCATION** 

## Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

August 2019 - Present

Ph.D. in Machine Learning - Advisor: Prof. Le Song

## Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

August 2014 - May 2017

B.S in Computer Science, Applied Statistics - Graduated with Highest Distinction

**EXPERIENCE** 

## Georgia Institute of Technology: Research Assistant

August 2019 - Present

• Researching temporal and graph neural network architectures to predict disease progression with electronic health records.

#### **Astound: Data Scientist**

*July 2017 – June 2019* 

- Researched and engineered human-in-the-loop machine learning systems to improve data quality.
   Method developed is optimized to reduce human annotator feedback while maximizing the performance of deep learning models. Resulting paper accepted at KDD'18.
- Developed transfer learning methods to improve a deep learning model performance given limited data.

#### Undergraduate Researcher: Advertisement Real Time Bidding Predictions August 2015 – May 2017

- Tested various deep learning architectures to predict customer clicks on the iPinYou advertisement dataset. Achieved high prediction scores even with sparse positive click data.
- Utilized an external GPU setup to speed up convolutional network training by a factor of 80.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Active Deep Learning to Tune Down the Noise in Labels

**K. Samel**, and X. Miao

In Proceedings of the 24th ACM SIGKDD International Conference on Knowledge Discovery & Data Mining (KDD'18). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 685-694. [PDF]

Predicting Advertisement Clicks Using Deep Networks: Interpreting Deep Learning Models

## K. Samel, X. Wang, and Q. Liu

In The Journal of Purdue Undergraduate Research: Vol. 7, Article 8. [PDF]

## **GRANTS & AWARDS**

- Georgia Tech President's Fellowship (2019 2023)
- NSF GRFP Honorable Mention: Relational Recursive Models for Trustable Medical Diagnoses (2019)
- KDD Startup Research Award (2018)
- NSF Mentoring Through Critical Transition Points in the Mathematical Sciences: Purdue Statistics Living Learning Community (Grant No. 1246818) (2016 2017)
- Purdue Presidential Scholarship (Awarded for 2014 2018)

## PENDING PATENTS

Active Deep Learning to Reduce Noise in Labels

Karan Samel, Xu Miao, Zhenjie Zhang, Masayo Iida, and Naghi Prasad

Framework for Building and Sharing Machine Learning Components Xu Miao, Masayo Iida, Zhenjie Zhang, **Karan Samel**, Adil Mohammed, Baiji He, Ankit Arya, and Naghi Prasad